okay
committee how do you see uh
because I think
commercial lines in general has has been
also one of the segments which have been
competitive over the years
and if you recollect uh almost about
three years back the insurers have
stepped in and said that in case if you
want to Avail reinsurance capacity given
that it's a high exposure segment you
have to price it at a particular level
of pricing
um so since then in the in those next
two years if you had seen from an icel
number standpoint we had kind of grown
faster than the market
but that's how we see his opportunity
for growth whenever the market collects
on price then the Focus Shift to service
and relatively we're able to exhibit a
much better outcome in so far as bucket
growth is concerned and more importantly
our focus on underwriting Still Remains
the Same
the very recent change that you're
talking about will also mean that on the
commercial lines portfolio today the
wordings are largely the same between
players in the market so therefore even
if you want to offer a differentiated
coverage or a term which is uh relevant
for a particular company or a sector
honestly between players we are not able
to do that so that's a change that will
happen again this particular change of
deregulation of wordings is again a
positive from a longer term perspective
from a short term again it could be it
could lead to some kind of price
Corrections also that's possible because
some players may want to give a term
which may not be so attractive for the
corporate or for the company concerned
which not that every cockpit understands
the significance of the birding so
therefore in the process if the
decisioning tends to base on price
that it's pretty much possible that it
could lead to some kind of uh
competition or maybe some kind of
moderation in pricing but long run I
think sensible companies understand what
risks they are exposed to and therefore
in the process it should be beneficial
but short term there is possible
was you know saying fire you know is
essentially what we're talking about
Direction happened in 2009 that is when
the pricing was kind of deregulated and
the wordings were you know still kept uh
you know uh what was there in the uh
soil tariff now different products have
different you know mechanisms or
something like liability for example was
never tariff so wordings were always you
know free and all of us you know as
companies have you know evolved you know
as far as those individual wordings are
concerned so what is being discussed
currently on the wording part is
basically allowing flexibility on the
property you know wordings it's also
very you know relevant to see that if
you look at the fire Market there is a
small risk the mid risk and the larger
risk even today the large risk can be
offered you know covers which are Beyond
tariff you know so anything which is
more than 2500 crores are some insured
uh the wordings can be agreed on a case
to case basis and it is supported by the
reinsurance
one of the strong advantages of the
Indian market was for example when covet
you know kind of returns at that point
at that contractor there was contractual
certainty you know in fact if you look
at what has happened in the
international markets you know some of
the wordings were slightly you know
because no one could see that you know
covet can be a situation which can
result into business Interruption losses
and some of these you know losses did
come you know to the international
markets and and went through a court uh
you know a process so when gopal is
talking about
you know challenges uh these are some of
the challenges that if you introduce a
wording without thinking through the the
you know consequences for the wording
which exists in the market
they're well understood by the customers
by the intermediary so even if you want
to sell a product you know the
intermediary of the channel should feel
comfortable explaining the problem you
know product proposition to the
to the customer the surveyors are used
to using you know these wordings to
assess the claims so whenever a new uh
flexibility in inverting uh you know
definition is going to come uh you know
this is positive from a long-term
perspective because again you know the
insurance will only give capacities you
know to players who understand you know
the focus on the risk is is would get
enhanced but in the short term it might
cause you know this this disruption so
modern competition I think it is the
ability of people to understand what
they're giving and and you know as it
manifests you know so so till that time
you know the product is very controlled
uh you know unknown Expo the probability
of an unborn exposure you assuming
exposure is less but you know once it is
uh you know 0.3 uh some bit of a
learning time might kind of come true
yeah because I think what whatever also
happen sorry the point which you made
related to that which you said that we
like the situation once uh that that uh
policy has got washed out and service
levels are going to be elevated that's
why we want to come in and make
aggressive investment and also start
writing business
but you still punctuated by saying that
towards the tail end which is what
you're making a point that there is
still a potential because what could
happen rise like competition still to
clear out because what will happen is
let's just imagine a situation right
today if it's a Well informed corporate
then they will understand the wordings
quite efficient effectively which is the
point that your ankur made when it comes
to very large risk largest exposures are
well understood by corporates and in any
which ways it will be significantly
reinsured the corporate also understands
the risk reasonably well and therefore
they know what to cover and therefore
whether the languages or the coverages
are adequate or not but that may not be
the same level of understanding when you
go down the Curve now because today
there was not so much of a challenge
because the coverage was uniform every
player in the market staff for a
standard uniform wordings in so far as
those policies are concerned
going ahead the moment it will get
deregulated you may start seeing
differentiated wordings being offered by
different players in the market
now what this could lead to for example
you as a corporate may say that Isis
Lombard is giving me a wording it is
related to that is a price
you may choose your decision basis price
and you may in the process be willing to
let's say
accept the wording whatever is being
offered by insurance company a
whereas Insurance Company B will
possibly do a fair assessment of
actually the type of risk that you are
exposed to
and suggest a language which is
appropriate for you from a risk
management standpoint and in the process
the price for that particular coverage
or wordings could be slightly more than
what let's say company has been offering
now in order to understand this
differentiation possibly will take some
time so you may see players taking calls
basis going with company a pricing but
you may realize that and the claim
experience happens
you're not possibly ending up getting
the benefits of claims so hence which is
why we are saying short term there could
be some challenges including maybe some
moderation in pricing but longer it is
very very positive so that's one change
you will see
the second is again again just a Fallout
of this particular change
today the market largely operates on a
coinsurance Market which is I mean not
that every company will be able to
absorb let's say risks worth thousands
of crores
so they tend to kind of co-share the
risk with multiple insurance companies
again the language being the same across
all players in the market and the way
the coinsurance Market work currently
works is one of the player is identified
as a leader which the customer decides
and the rest of the insurance companies
with whom the risk is shared act as
followers to the risk with whatever
share percentages are but again as I
said the larger thought process being
the language is largely uniform in terms
of wordings today it will strike at a
move away from a coincidence Market into
a subscription Market
which is to say that I mean when or even
before I talk about subscription under
the Commissioners mechanism the customer
ends up paying the premium to One
Insurance company that particular
insurance company then does the
settlements of Premium claims with other
followers who are co-sharers of risks as
I said but the language being the same
but moving ahead everything will move
into a subscription model because
insurance
the customer decides to make me as the
leader I may want to offer a wording
which is to the advantage of the
customer and that for my price point
could also be very different as compared
to some other insurance company to whom
the corporate may want to still act as a
let's say a co-sharer of risk
they may still want to kind of place
that risk separately so effectively you
will see individual risk getting placed
separately with each of the companies
and in the process it could again stand
beneficial for the corporate concerts
because the risk involved of two five
thousand cores of potential killing is
something yeah yeah that then gets a
little washed away so that gets a little
washed away which actually again is a
positive for let's say companies which
are relatively better on balance sheet
because today
a corporate for whatever reason may
actually end up giving a five percent
share just for to some other so let's
say xyzer insurance company tomorrow
because I'm giving a wording Which is
far more beneficial to that corporate he
or she will think twice before giving
any let's say even a five or ten percent
share to some other players and not
every company will be able to observe
the same type of we will be able to give
the same type of wordings so hence long
run very positive short-term maybe some
descriptions
of the subscription or it is one is that
you know their ability to give cover I
think the biggest another very big
Advantage is what happens today is so if
you are the customer and I am the leader
I collect the premium from you and I
distribute it to the followers you know
when there's a claim I do the assessment
I pay the claim to you and I collect it
from the coinsurance so from a freight
risk perspective you are kind of
insulated now the moment a subscription
Market happens you will have to give me
premium from only my share and to him
for this share and the real thing will
be claim recovery right so tomorrow you
know a balance sheet a small balance
sheet size you know a solvency of say
1.56 would you be comfortable giving
that whole Insurance because you are not
taking ownership of also recovering that
you know from the from the coinsure
directly which which basically will be
an advantage for companies who have lost
you know bigger bandages so the onus
then comes on both to the customer the
customer to search for this yes with
that I mean so in terms of evolution as
it said that deregulation and that so
how much of that is sort of playing out
right now it's effective April 23 has to
speak right so highlights yeah yeah
deregulation of commercial buildings is
finalized there's no committee which is
trying to discuss and finalize it's
already finalized that's going to be
leader so I'm just saying that those are
those discussions are definitely
happening but definitely it's likely to
come into practice from April 23. and
how much of the business is actually
coming to these large players like large
office
so for us if you look at again the three
categories what ankur spoke about which
is small corporate mid and let's say
very large corporates which understands
these wordings far more effectively on
the large risk for Segment I think we'll
be present in almost close to about 75
to 80 of the risks
we are pretty much there you know pretty
much every account we have a very large
proportion the rest of it is an
opportunity
but what we have been doing on the
commercial lines is every year we have
been a pretty Market
s
on the largest category
we are almost about you're almost in 75
to 80 of the accounts we are already
present but presenting what the question
it could be multiple proportions I mean
say in some accounts will be we will be
with the leader with a 51 market share
in some accounts I could be with the
market share of let's let's say a share
of 30 percent
is that sort of penetration that's a
penetration of the number of accounts
which are there in that 75 to 80 of the
accounts Isis Lombard has got his
participation what share it could vary
between risk today depending on the uh
appetite that we may have also to kind
of write those risks
the number of business which is shifted
every year you know that number very
difficult to give you a specific number
to it because each risk could be
different as I said as some let's say a
risk which is worth 10 000 crores even I
may not want to take let's say 51 share
in that particular risk
at many times because even I have my own
rescapitate in terms of how much we can
observe and how much we would want to
kind of depending on my reinsurance
capacity that I'm buying so hence I may
take an exposure which we think are
comfortable whereas if it's a risk which
is worth let's say a thousand crores
their assisted I end up taking the risk
which is up to let's say 51 for example
so it could vary between risk to risk
all that I'm saying is the presence of
us matters a lot because we are kind of
pretty much there in every account of
majority of the accounts of that
particular category the small handmade
is you said is an opportunity I.E we are
not present or very small so we are
pretty much there if you look at overall
commercial lines across categories we
will have a market share anywhere
ranging between 12 to 15 percent
for the category as a whole whether you
take fire whether you take engineering
whether you take Marine cargo Marine
cargo by the way we are industry leaders
fire engineering Marine liability all of
them
we would have a market share range
anywhere between 12 to 15. so out of the
total commercial line
the maximum impact of this should be on
the Fire
predominantly
yeah anyway sitting 75 percent of that
business right not necessarily it again
is a function incrementally we are not
necessarily seeding so much because we
are writing more of small and mid
corporate policies as well which were
relatively the extent of reinsurance is
lower uh so again it's not a fixed
percentage that we reinsured 78 of the
risk it's again a purely a function of
the point that I made on a risk which is
let's say ten thousand crores I may
possibly tend to have a relatively
slightly higher proportion of
reinsurance as compared to risk which is
relatively lower in size
handling or are you seeing any of course
because given that given that whatever
we are seeing globally I think there are
clearly catastrophic events for forget
about globally first even if you look at
the Indian market
on an average you should talk about one
catastrophic event a year in the past
today you look at it at least two or
three cat events happen on any on an era
year-on-year basis so therefore there is
also more the reason for S2 is to be far
more sensible on underwriting now coming
back to your point on will the rates
Harden yes there will definitely be
indications of rates that will get
hardened as we speak and quarter four is
a cycle at which we kind of end up
negotiating our contracts of reinsurance
renewals because typically it's an
annual renewal buying that we end up
doing on the reinsurance front in
general if you look at our experience on
underwriting we have been largely
writing the book at a combined of 100
our commercial lines has been extremely
profitable and therefore the relative
outcome that we have been able to
exhibit to the reinsurers have also been
positive
and hence to that extent which is why
you would have been hearing us
consistently talk about two things one
incrementally we have always been able
to improve our panel of reinsurance whom
we are operating with just to kind of
make sure that we don't run with any
credit risk even the point that occurred
made and equally we try and make sure
that we are able to get better terms of
reinsurance now better terms could be
again on two two counts one is the
commission on reinsurance that we get as
an income we will obviously try and
maximize that and two for some of the
catastrophic protections that we have to
take there is a cost of reinsurance that
we required to pay so that again as the
exposures are increasing we will
obviously try and make sure that
relative to the increase in exposures
the cost increase is not as much so
those are the two ways to which we kind
of manage but obviously maybe we will
come back in April and give you more
better insights once we complete the
renewal cycle but as we speak obviously
there is a rate hardening that is kind
of clearly an indication but the impact
could be far more for some of the other
companies which have been more adverse
on there and writing
let's look at type of range this is what
we do one is we do a proportionary
insurance as the term proportionate
reinsurance indicates for whatever risk
that I've assumed
I decide to let's say part with a
proportion of that business let's say 40
percent so as an example okay I'm just
giving this an example it could be 20
and some 17 others 14 some I'm just
giving as an example so the term
proportionate insurance is whatever risk
that I assume a proportion of that risk
is what I'm giving to the Range Rover
which is why it's called the
proportionate reinsurance
on that proportion of reinsurance that I
do with a set of reinsurance Partners
whom we have decided to work with they
give me a commission on reinsurance
which acts as an income to me
now that Commission on reinsurance is a
function of your quality of underwriting
if you are exhibiting a book which is
relatively better then obviously the
terms of reinsurance commission that you
get also tends to be far better
historically on the commercial lines as
I said we have been running it fairly
profitably profitable therefore
the terms of commission income that we
have got have generally been favorable
uh so that's what we will try even for
the current renewal cycle as well
the second element of reinsurance is
post the proportionate reinsurance and
by the way every risk whatever you
assume there is a four percent
obligatory that has to go to GIC which
is a General Insurance Corporation of
India that's mandated by guidelines uh I
the proportion part we were talking
about was more beyond the four percent
um so now let's assume whatever
proportion you decided to do it on a
proportionate basis the rest of the risk
after the obligatory is on your net
account
I mean what you retain on the net again
that net could be quite large let's say
in a thousand crore exposure even if you
decide to let's say do a 40 reinsurance
and let's say four percent of obligatory
all of that put together in 44 still 56
of the book is quite large you may not
be able to kind of observe that loss
because in the event if that loss
happens your your balance sheet should
be able to absorb those uh impact so
which is why we enter into what we call
as a non-proportional or excess of loss
protection
which is to largely address losses
resulting from Individual Peak instances
or it could be losses resulting from
catastrophic events so you have to
protect both
to make sure that again you manage your
p l well and more importantly you are
not putting your balance sheet to risk
just to sort of put paraphrase that is
similar to kind of taking a group in
short of the group of business you've
written that the second tier right so
one you've done a proportionate which
you've done very clear you know the risk
you've taken and you've been paid for
the better underwriting that but very
well correct the balance 60 itself is
very large exposure yeah and you are
doing it at two ends yes as you said
rightly again one is for individual
risks that I'm protecting and then and
two is a collective risk Collective risk
that I'm protecting so at a point of
time why one risk can get impacted let's
say if there's a fire in this building
right and this exposure is literally
thousand crores so if this entire Fire
gets if this entire building gets gutted
for whatever reason so the probability
is less but let's assume for a moment it
gets completely created in which case
there's a thousand crore loss can I take
thousand crew and let's assume in my
example I decided a proportional
Insurance of 40 all inclusive which
means 600 crores will come and hit by
net do I have the capacity to take 600
pros of loss on my p l is a question
mark that I am seeking where which is
where I said I will take enter into a
non-proportional or excess of loss
protection
to manage that extended growth of
exposure to say that in the event of
individual large losses my risk on the p
l will not exceed a particular rupee
value that's a part of my reinsurance
contract on the non-proportional or on
the excess of loss that's a rupee value
that I will negotiate so in this case
whatever the threshold is let's say 50
crosses so I made you said yeah
but clearly what you're trying to do I
think you've said it I'm just trying to
learn it which is you're trying to as
you said optimize both the p l and the
balance sheet by paying a lump sum 50
crores
you are you're basically trying to
create a leverage on the other portion
that in in a very simplistic fashion
right basically on the single risk and
as you set the collectivity yeah so I'll
I'll just close the loop on the single
and then I'll come to the collective
risk also so on this single effectively
in my example of 600 crores I may not
want to take 600 I may choose to keep
only let's say 15 rows at 50 crores
whatever that number is so I am saying
my pnl I'm okay to take 50 crores right
the rest of the things I'm kind of again
parting it out to the panel of
reinsurance before I am required to pay
that cost so that's the second thing
that I need to work as a part of my
arrangements renewals to make sure that
the cost of reinsurance of protecting
that individual Peak losses I manage it
within acceptable levels now it is quite
possible an event can impact multiple
risks at the same time flood
or any other catastrophic event an
earthquake if it happens it can impact
multiple disks at the same time
so that again when I collectively put
all those exposures of the net it could
be a very large proportion so there
again what I do is again enter into a
non-proportional arrangement to say that
from an isil numbered perspective in the
event of a catastrophic loss which
impacts multiple of risks at the same
time
again I am willing to take a net impact
of x Indian rupees Beyond which it will
be paid by a panel of reinsurers now
again it is not that the panel of Ruin
stores are going to pay you indefinite
or unlimited it comes with a cap
but the cap that we buy we test it every
year this is the exposures that we take
and what we have seen is the level of
free insurance that we buy
we kind of test it to the worst of the
situations that we've experienced in the
past for example Mumbai floods is the
worst of the floods that we have
experienced historically for the last
several years
and on the incremental exposure it is
not that we go back to 2005 exposures we
have been increasing exposure since then
on today's exposures if an event of a
Mumbai flood was to similarly get
recurred then what is the extent of my
ranged runs layers that will get
consumed by virtue of the loss that one
could experience
generally what we have seen it gets
consumed to the tune of our envelope in
15 to 20 percent
and that's what we model which means the
level of protection that we buy is still
fairly large enough 15 to 20 would you
mean one-fifth that means you only one
five x more that's the way to kind of
look at it I will not say we have bought
more right it's just that we want to be
conservative
we have bought for a fairly large event
which can give us Comfort saying that
even if that event of that magnitude
happens our reinsurers are there to kind
of pay for the losses now this could be
different for different players
some companies may choose to buy a limit
of reinsurance Which is far more limited
because the end of the rates are risk
reward right you have to pay a cost
corresponding to which you get a
protection
company may choose to kind of be far
more aggressive in their Arrangements
buying philosophy and they may choose to
buy a limit which is far more
conservative I mean far more aggressive
just to kind of protect some costs today
right but when the event happens is when
you start to pay a price
and again live examples the same Mumbai
flood examples two companies went under
I don't want to name the companies but
two companies protection was significant
inadequate they had to depend beyond the
limit that they had brought in so far as
their insurance coverage
even in your Netflix
so those are examples so so hence you
have to be very very careful in the
extent of reinsurance buy that you do
besides of of the obvious commercials
that you kind of end up doing the
transaction the other aspect is how much
you buy in the SEC the next extension is
that you know when I need to make a
recovery do you have the financial
capability of paying that or not yeah
the Quality quality of the reinsurance
yeah which is what you said the panel
will be here
absolutely one is the absolute
commercials that what is the cause
for example I can work with the Triple B
also and maybe get a 10 lower cost or
maybe two percent extra commission but
when the claim would come you know now
the point is short tail exposure long
tail exposure so there are multiple
passage to kind of look at it it's an
engineering project what I'm writing
today the claim will come after 10 years
is that entity going to be there and I
want to make a recovery so I think this
is what we try to do uh you know from a
refunds first 50 so now just to put
everything together now with this iib
you know think about this deterfing you
know uh uh kind of coming obviously
commercial and businesses require
Insurance you know now this is going to
create some short-term you know
challenges but at the same time a
long-term perspective and the initial as
the global Majors you know who are the
top five or the top 10 bringing showers
they would then want to partner with
companies who have a very sound you know
risk understanding and uh and a practice
and that is where the differentiation
should set you know should kind of start
to cover
right so I mean it's a good balance
between this proportionate selling out
that's what you talked about and one is
what you pay out further for protecting
the individual losses and uh
so this proportional again is also at a
portfolio level yeah you know so we do
an annual contract and whatever we write
depending upon the size and nature you
know that session automatically happens
but for your underwriting skills are you
sort of being bidded up and paid better
yeah absolutely that's it that's it the
insurance want to get your exactly
exactly because
manages the reinsurance end of the day
we actually end up in a situation where
we have more takers than which may not
be true for every players in the market
it all depends on the as I said at the
end of the rates all depends on the
quality one rating that you do
if you see on an average out of the 100
rupees of Premium that we write as a
company we retain 70 roughly and
possibly our extent of reinsurance is to
the tune of 25 30 percent and the reason
is because today if you look at almost
more than two-thirds of a business is
motor and health
which are relatively small ticket
exposures as compared to a property
exposure
and on the retail lines I kind of pretty
much written everything Levi said the
four percent obligatory which I talked
about from the commercial it's much
higher commercially too tired because
it's 670 because the risk exposures are
higher the risk exposures are higher so
you need to manage the risks
appropriately so given the choice
a couple of years because of tariffs and
because of all this issue there could be
some pressure on this business which was
probably the most profitable in the last
two three years given the issues with
the auto so which is what we believe I
think all the changes in the guidelines
or regulations which are coming through
as we speak over the last whatever has
got announced in the last six to nine
months
most of them will be short-term
challenging because there could be for
various reasons but long run it is
significantly beneficial for companies
like Isis local
wanted to move into retail lines of
business and I have a very basic
question so if we look at if you look at
the interest industry it is the Private
Industry The Profit market share of you
know is much more concentrated than the
premium market share so basically these
insurers had only three or four make
money right what do you do differently
versus the others which keeps you
consistently on the right side and what
makes it difficult for the other players
to generate profit in this industry one
is the intent
so that's the starting point I'm I'm
trying to be as straightforward as what
it can be it's very simple right now you
you look at till 2008 there were 16 17
players post 2008 another 16 17 players
entered the market
the question is what did what is the
approach that each of these companies
took
did they wanted to create something
differentiated in the market to your
point on are they creating something
which is
a moat or a USB or an advantage
whichever way you want to kind of call
it as or did they go with an approach of
driving using price as a means to gain
some market share possibly many
companies took the latter part to say
that I will use price as a liver and
they obviously exactly to your point on
some of the key Motor Lines are easy to
tap into
but the end outcome is what we largely
look at I mean today you look at the
tale of companies which are operating at
a combined which is significantly
elevated and therefore corresponding to
that the solvency is equally and that's
in stressed for them to kind of exhibit
that for a relatively longer period of
time
the call that ICC Lombard took even
during this times when the market was
very very aggressive at different points
of time this is not just in one instance
which we have spoken in the past
multiple instance in the past we have
seen different segments exhibiting
periods of vibration
it's the question of what is it that the
institution wants to drive
as a company our philosophy for Isis
Lombard has been to drive profitable
growth as a theme and that's something
they have done in the past that's
something that we are talking about even
as we look forward
well that's a call that each company has
to take what is it that you want to
drive so that will that's the first
foremost starting point
the second is particularly in the retail
lines as all of you understand
distribution becomes a very very
important level
now how robust distribution enable you
are able to kind of create also leads
into economies of scale and with that if
you are also able to blend technology as
a part of it then to the direction
you're also able to drive it far more
efficiently in terms of overall
productivity gains now there again if
you look at motor
we kind of clearly built a lot a lot of
let's say mode or strength insofar as
initially kind of focusing a lot on
point of dealership
so it was our own I mean employees of
Isis number do act as Field Force
present at the point of dealerships
built that relationship over years and
today therefore
given the years of working with them we
believe we are able to kind of possibly
get a share of portfolio which is to our
liking and this may not be true in every
dealership touch point we will obviously
want ideally prefer to 100 of our
preferred segments but many times you
may not be able to get that but we will
try as much as possible to get a
relative leave better share of mix of
portfolios that we want to under it so
therefore staying invested in
distribution and creating that
relationship obviously plays a very very
important and today if you look at on
motor of the total number of dealerships
that we have roughly we are present in
almost about 55 to 60 of the total
number of dealership counters on the
private car side ah so that clearly acts
as a huge uh Advantage for us
more importantly than what we also try
to create as a capability today is on
the claims front I mean all of us know
your dealer is not having an unlimited
space in terms of turnaround for uh the
vehicle servicing
and through use of technology and the
use of instaspect app we have been able
to do a live video streaming of the
entire survey process
and in the process you are actually able
to help the workshop create better
margins
which actually kind of quite resonates
quite well for the garage person and
therefore they're willing to part part
businesses with companies like Isis and
robot who are similar like-minded set of
companies are willing to kind of place
businesses with those type of companies
so that again access a huge advantage to
us
increasingly what we're also getting to
is if you see many of the motor vehicle
repairs could be when motorcycle damages
could be either repaired or it could be
replaced I mean some of the parts may
require a replacement
generally the procurement of these parts
would be done by let's see the garage
person through third-party suppliers
and each of them may be kind of possibly
placing order separately for replacement
of Parts what we are also trying to see
can we act as aggregators of those parts
and make them available for the various
garages so in the process you are able
to again try to strike some kind of an
advantage relative to pricing and these
are all small amounts which can start
making a difference in the overall cost
of claims so that's another thing that
we are kind of significantly driving
the last piece is the decision to
completely insource the entire claim
adjudication process I mean this is
again a decision that motor specifically
we took it several years back even on
health we took 10 years back so we don't
work with any of the third party
external claim adjudicators whether it
is on motor or whether it is on health
so we have automobile Engineers who act
as
uh over on the roles of Isis low bar and
we have doctors who are those devices
they act as adjudicators of claim and
they are able to create a lot of value
to us
because they are able to have direct we
are able to have direct supervision over
them they are able to look at claims
between similar type of claim incidences
at different locations different places
different models and compare and see the
need for any of those changes to be made
or the repairs to be done including
questioning hospitals for example as to
why a particular treatment is being done
so the whole objective is to try and
make sure that the overall cost of claim
whether it is motor or health is kept
under check those are some of the
attributes that we have been able to
create over years which we believe is
acting as trends for us
in terms of growth
not just growth competition pricing so
the good part is competition as what we
have been speaking over the last few
earnings call at least one
if you look at the aggressiveness what
all of you refer to
motor has led to a combined of 124
percent
now in our last 22 years we have never
seen motor of combined ratios at 124 so
that tells you a story in terms of how
competitive the market had become in the
last few years
gently in motor we see cycles of
competition but typically they come back
is within a maybe an 18 to 24 month
cycle this time the cycle has been much
more longer again for understandable
reasons because we saw a Perfection of
many things that came in the last during
covet period all of those are behind us
every aspect of it so therefore there is
no reason this 124 combined can be a
sustaining one and hence in the recent
cause we have been talking about it and
that's what you're seeing on the ground
as well
most of the players were very aggressive
in the last 12 months seems to be kind
of talking starting to talk to get
reasonable
now I am not saying that suddenly the
number of 124 has moved to 100 but there
is a definitely been a change from 124
to lower than that number
it is pricing people have started to
look at the overall there is this
proposed draft on expense of management
which caps the limit on the overall cost
of what we're doing business at 30 there
are a lot of players who are beyond that
30 threshold and in the case of health
insurance business companies the cap is
at 35. a lot of companies are Beyond 35
percent and clearly the regulatory is
talking about a Glide path to bring it
down within those thresholds whatever
that limits are so there is stress on
those players to become far more
efficient in the overall cost of doing
business so again people are starting to
get far more reasonable
so all of this is definitely like a long
term positive
because we have again in this period why
we would have slightly underperformed on
growth but we are not we are not shied
away from continuing to make those
investments in distribution service and
technology so we are kind of positioned
to capitalize the opportunity for growth
uh you set the commercial lens obviously
insist on writing it at 100 that's all
commercial lines has generally been very
profitable for us yeah but you said you
write it at 100 that could be less than
100 also
yeah and 100 less than 100 is the
combined ratio for ISO number on the
commercial portfolio and for both of you
talk about yourself versus the motor
really which is why we are
underperforming the market right so if
you look at growth so you clearly not
done we have consciously for example you
look at our mix of Private Car two
wheeler and commercial vehicles
last year mix private car was roughly
about 55 percent
my two wheeler was roughly about 27 28
and my commercial vehicles was roughly
about 17 18 percent
if you look at current year my mix of
private car is less than 50. it's close
to 49 my two wheeler has been available
in strength it has been more or less
maintained at 27 percent
commercial vehicles for the reasons that
we have explained but that mix is closer
to about 23 24 23 to 25 percent
so the competition has been
significantly elevated in the private
car space and hence it's not that we
have vacated distribution that's very
very important for us we have possibly
moderated shares in some of the
encounters with a question sorry uh
is there a fleet and a that's a group
level in the auto side also you eating
as an example let's say I believe Uber
has a lot of their proprietary taxis
that they have bought and then given
them on a rental model to the driver
Partners as they're called yeah but it's
Uber's insurance so commercial vehicles
generally could work on fleets as well
uh but I'm saying but not for uh not for
Provisions private current two wheelers
will be more individual specific is
really private I mean largely
predominantly I would say
one thing which
was very clear is to get more number of
players and it looked from its
commentary that he wants his competition
to be a lot more intense than you know
what you think the motor is often
exceptionally competitive market but
yeah how do you see the profit tool you
know I mean why yes most of the
cocktails are still at the early stage
of development and you know they will be
investing but how do you see the profit
pool really emerging for the sector yeah
and frankly after listening to this
presentation
foreign
so which is what which is why I started
off in the initial saying that the
regulatory reforms whatever it is being
announced shot in the short run there
could be disruptions in the long run
definitely they are far more beneficial
and let me close loop on the licenses
part that you referred to now if you
look at the larger thought person I'm
sure the chairman must have spoken about
that he would have started with the 2047
philosophy which is insurance for all
right vision and penetration for all
that's a larger theme within which this
is being driven at so if you look at the
thought process of the regulator is
similar to what is there on the banking
side
if you look at banking pretty much there
are different categories of banks which
cater to needs of customers
whatever their needs are which is why
you have a full-fledged Bank you have a
small Finance Bank you have an npfc you
have a regional Rural Bank you have a
cooperative bank now each of them cattle
to different segments of customers
larger objective is banking for all a
similar thought process is there on the
insurance side to make sure that there
are differentiated licenses that are
being issued
and each of them possibly caters to the
specific requirements that insurance
customers may have and in the process
Drive the agent of increasing Insurance
penetration
so hence we will have to see what type
of companies get a license
if these are Niche product specific
geography specific companies who want to
come and do business
it prices number does not impact us so
much
but it may impact in the segment or in
the geography where that particular
company is going to get a license to
but if it is someone which comes like a
plan India license similar to let's say
what Isis number is doing then there
could be some temporary stress like
similar to what I explained in 2008
there were 16 17 players since then
there were another 17 players added to
the market so we did see stress getting
exhibited but the challenge is today the
market is already 119 combined
now the ability of unless you come and
tell me that this particular private
company is willing to come with a deep
Capital burn model
then that's a different story
but we don't think at least in the
private space
companies willing to come and have an
extended period of deep Capital World
model
and two it's not a capitalistic
free-flowing thing I mean that's what we
have seen
thirdly thanks to reality checks not
just in Insurance in multiple sectors
this price to revenue LED valuations
have got kind of come back to some
reasonableness and therefore
there will definitely be aggression
which could be exhibited by some of
these entrants but that's the nature of
the market
but you know just to follow up on that
if you
were like 190 combined ratio for
industry is actually not healthy no
apparently I mean and while you know I
take all the points that you know it's
under penetrated indeed Insurance do you
think the way
I mean to continue with 119 percent kind
of not ratio on a combined research for
an extended period of time it's more
like a weakening you know kind of a I
mean is it really that healthy I mean
what has been the presentation from
players to the regulator and hasn't been
any dialogue I said you know I mean
there'll be players like
you know Echo doing like really you know
120 130 kind of loss ratios is there
something concerning for you as not just
as a market leader using share that's
fine but you see this is like a really
big structural risk for the profit pool
off so which is what we had mentioned I
think for us according to from our
standpoint
124 combined just on motor specific
cannot be a sustainable one
okay right so that's one change and I as
I said already we are seeing signs of a
lot more players who are very aggressive
in the last 12 months starting to talk
to get far more reasonable and
reasonable is on both counts both in
terms of pricing
and two the proposed draft that I talked
about on the expensive management
guideline
it's not that players are operating at a
combat of 95 96 in which case some of
the players who are more than let's say
the defined Norms could actually let's
say get a some kind of a breather it's
not the case
all those many of the players who are
Beyond a defined threshold are operated
combined which is significantly adverse
so therefore the Headroom that could
possibly be available
may not be existent at all thirdly if
you look at generally the philosophy I'm
sure the chairman has spoken on that as
well
increasingly the regulator is also
wanting to make sure that the overall
cost of sourcing of businesses is
reasonable and which is why even under
the proposed eom guidelines for even
those companies which currently are
exceeding the threshold they have to
specifically put out a Glide path within
three years to bring down within the
thresholds that's one and even otherwise
they are in general saying the overall
cost of business is to reduce
so in all fairness now to close loop the
market has to kind of get better than
the 119 combined
we went through Auto disruption now if
we speak to other mature player like you
most of the people are looking at retail
health and competition over there has
increased in few of the conversations
with Hospital companies they also then
said you know the discount that they
used to uterine insurance companies has
reduced significantly you also and your
call mentioned that you are looking more
selling off or increasing the mix into
health insurance what's happening there
is
yeah so I think um so far as one on the
health insurance definitely a preferred
segment for us is what we've explained
and the two categories that we are in is
Corporate and retail on the corporate
side again just to kind of refresh last
year we did talk about affecting a price
revision of 15 to 20 percent
in reality we ended up with a price
division much higher than that
and over and above that in the current
renewal cycle which is for the current
22-23 Financial year renewals we have
still been able to get a reasonable
price increase over and above the last
year's price change
and despite that in so far as customer
retentions are concerned on the
corporate side we have not seen any drop
in our customer attentions
so hence kind of that's doing very well
one one thing the combined ratio over
the corporation combined issue for the
corporate will always be so for for us
it's quite okay because we do write
relatively large corporates and at the
same time small and mid corporate
companies uh when you look at the
combination of both of this will lead to
a loss ratio of anywhere between 94 95
percent
and generally the delivery of these
services are directly with these
companies and therefore that's largely a
single digit cost of uh whatever
sourcing and then hence on a blended
basis the portfolio will run at a
combined ratio over around 100 to 101
percent
I talked about large corporates and
small and with corporate code put
together so loss ratio about 94.95
single digit cost of acquisition and
therefore a blended basis combined ratio
of 100 to 101 percent
higher right because you have higher so
not necessarily it's accomplished it
again there's a relative cost of
distribution will be far lower because
the competition at the large corporate
is very high that's all so we don't
write those very large bfsi and Tech
accounts
because that's exactly what happens and
those accounts may be there this year
next year I may not even have it
okay
which is the reason why I've said we
don't write any of those very very large
PFS and Tech accounts largely we try to
build a book Which is far more granular
so that you're able to get some
reasonable price and the overall
portfolio experience on the combined
ratio is within our acceptable
thresholds
um on the retail side
retail benefit is again a critical
illness offering generally profitable
last two years we did have some
Challenge on the overall contribution of
retail benefit because of the decision
of the bank to stop discontinuing
third-party retail benefit offering and
two even the scale of disbursements of
Institutions with whom we had a tie up
to offer retail benefit also was scaled
down again both of them are behind us
which is why if you look at our current
nine month deck on the non-icci bank
lead growth that's kind of growing at
about 45 but of course it has two
factors the scale of disbursements are
back and two is obviously on a lower
base so hence we love to kind of sustain
but the benefit business is kind of
doing well for us generally profitable
on the retail health and ability the
business that you're referring to it's
again a preferred segment for us and
that's an area where we're investing a
lot on building distribution
to your point on uh loss development
behavior of course that's something that
we keep watching
and we see if there is a need for us to
affect any kind of a price revision or
not for example if you remember the last
price solution that we took was in
quarter three of 2021 roughly a weighted
average price increase of eight percent
on the overall portfolio
currently as we speak we have affected a
price revision on the renewable book
which is 20 percent
so it's not that we have shied away from
affecting a price change
similar to wait and see in terms of what
as I said at end of the day on retail
Health Indemnity which is what we said
our loss ratios are within our
acceptable levels which is around that
65 to 70 kind of range
our cost of acquisition currently is in
the range of 35 to 40 percent which is
why we said on a blended basis my retail
Health Indemnity is running at a
combined ratio of 105 to 110. that's
primarily because we are at this point
of time investing on building that
distribution
early signs of the Investments playing
out to our advantage in line with what
we have been speaking but we're going to
sustain that even as we speak on an
ongoing basis
as as the revenue kicks in we should see
the benefit of efficiency of scale
payout which is what we have been kind
of talking about it's for the large
players
their expectation of 95 most uh these
prices are x 20 25 is that reasonable or
it still sounds like you will have to
wait for people to deliver 95 combined
though we believe retail Health
Indemnity from an ISO number standpoint
we would want to see the book Running at
a combined closer to 100 but is it good
that pipelines have been taken and it's
obviously good things so which is what
I'm saying so if you see we we took the
price decision in 2021 ahead of the
market
and then one year into it is where most
of the players kind of talked about a
price change right having said that the
point that I made on motor where we're
also acting as let's say spare parts
aggregators
similar thing is what we are trying to
do even on the health front to try and
see how again Sauron in-house claims
management team right so their objective
is to try and see how we can possibly
divert maybe India is a very one of the
hardly you will see in any other markets
where a customer doesn't inform the
insurance company before going for a
treatment
if that happens we are able to divert a
lot of the customers to Preferred
service providers where you're able to
get a better rate package rate and
therefore thereby you're able to keep
the overall cost of claims under check
so that's something that we increasingly
try and do to keep the overall cost of
claims under check to your point on
you're already seeing let's say
hospitals showing elevated Billings so
we consciously work on bringing bringing
that down but that we are able to
exhibit in largely I would say Tire two
entire three hospitals where relatively
the Insurance Billings is a much larger
proportion to the overall overall
revenues and therefore we are able to
get a better deal can I do that with the
tire a hospital no
because still insurance billing in their
overall revenues is a very very small
proportion so I'm not able to get the
best of the package rates so that we may
be slightly more in that sense higher on
the cost of claims but the larger
objective is to try and see through
various interventions keep the overall
cost of claims under check and in the
process the price point for the customer
is reasonable
the last piece which we're trying to do
is more the adoption of Il take care app
which is the same philosophy as what we
had on the commercial lines front which
is value-added services in the form of
more preventive more Wellness related
Behavior
our hypothesis is in the long run this
should hopefully translate into reduced
number of hospitalization but we are not
breaking anything right now in the
numbers what we are talking about
consequent to this
is about 65 to 70. 65 to 70
that with the mind corporate uh what you
said where the Lost numbers as high as
95 that's correct so how is that uh
contrast can you just explain that
because generally when I do a
negotiation with the corporates we'll
try to squeeze the maximum out of you
right so you're saying that
that slack or the less that you get out
of that so the product of the scale of
the pricing the pricing that you get
from a corporate is generally much much
lower right
and hence a sourcing cost is a single
digit number which is why I said which
is why I said on the aggregate when you
look at it from combined ratio
standpoint it is 100 101 kind of report
whereas when you look at retail right
the pricing is reasonably okay
the last ratio at which the book is
currently operating it is anywhere
between 65 to 70 percent right given the
Investments that we are making on
building distribution my cost of
distribution is currently at 35 to 40 so
therefore my current combined ratio the
retail Health Indemnity is 105 210
as the revenue kicks in on the
Investments that we are making
automatically we should be able to bring
down the combined from the 105 and
closer to a threshold of 100 that's a
thought process
I mean it's something that we've
obviously stayed away from yeah any I
mean how are we going to solve for that
because that's really a big growth
opportunity sitting there on the policy
aggregators platform you're saying we
are building our own capability ICC
lombard.com
yes so therefore it's far more efficient
and far more economical for us to kind
of build that platform but do you not
solve for growth if you actually so
honestly at this point of time maybe we
could be wrong at least for the forcible
future we don't see
Insurance in India completely moving
into a online space you still need a
multi-channel multi-distribution
multi-product approach for you to be
able to kind of source businesses across
different product segments take motor
the sheer convenience of a customer
getting a policy at the point of
dealership is not going to change
which is what we consciously track we
track what is the cost of distribution
that I have to pay to that platform
vis-a-vis the cost of digital marketing
which I do it on Isis lumbar.com
I find that to be far more efficient
so that's what I keep checking and what
the policy platforms do is correct
customer I can tell you this I've just
renewed this three months ago I had a
dozen calls before the domba guy
actually called and said Sarah policy
anymore and I was actually surprised
because obviously this data is now out
there and I asked each and every one of
them as a shareholder that where did you
get this data and they said available
there freely and at least a dozen people
have called is health or motor motor a
dozen people so I I mean I'm so even
practically I would like to think that
uh there is clearly an opportunity there
at least that's my sense and you've been
talking to us so when you say
multi-product multimodal multi-channel
distribution why not one of these as
well means you could continue to build
up you think that gets diluted if you go
on a platform no all that we are saying
is at this point of time the trade-off
between
the underwriting outcome of sourcing a
business through that channel is not
viable for us so it's not the
underwriting outcome and not just cat
it's nothing to do with only all that
I'm saying is from at the end of the day
I have to look at it from a writing
outcome right and for which in so far as
this selection is concerned we know
which it is to select so therefore
that's not challenged what is the next
element it's a cost of distribution now
from whatever the policy platforms does
they write in what they're doing
because they will obviously want to
maximize their earnings by looking at
which companies products they do they
want to push any company who's willing
to give them an incremental cost of
distribution is what they would want to
largely push
visibly that is what we compare on
building our own platform which is
islamba.com and if I have to spend money
on digital marketing to acquire a
customer what is it that I'm ending up
spending today I'm finding that to be
far more economical as compared to
paying it to a platform
rather I will build that's exactly what
we've done
that part is okay but I think one level
higher question of the marketplace
itself right which is to his point or
two individuals who do general motor
insurance every a couple of years or
every year also are you in some sense
losing market share at the market level
because not because of the platform not
because of the platform at least because
which is exactly the point that I'm
making at least in the Indian market we
don't see at least for the foreseeable
feature
sudden shift on people looking to go and
buying policies only through the
platform only through the platform
because we do track customer Journeys
right we do companies we do see
customers going to these platforms we do
see customers going and doing research
online right but the eventual decision
in many of the product lines
particularly on health for example they
end up doing a sale which is through our
agent through a friend or through some
form of a telephony assistance
I I think I mean reflective of the
personal Behavior so so so so so hence
but what is equally important to your
point it is important to create that
channel of sourcing so which is the
channel that we are investing in we are
building isosolumbar.com exactly to
address some customers who are maybe
informed who want to let's say get into
completely an online form of buying
that's the capability created
so insurance is not just about an
e-commerce sale where you end up buying
a product and that's the end of the
process
there's a service experience in fact
that's a product that we sell
that matters a lot
and also you layered it with the fact
that we're not sure of the quality of
the underwriting you made the two
distinct points
and then you said the market is
currently not ready on buying this
insurance online Etc
what part of your distribution that
you're creating
is potentially ready for the Plug and
Play If this Market were to evolve and
what evidence would you want to see so
today I've got a capability today today
today customers want to buy motor
insurance online can go to my website
and buy potentials online but only from
you let's say right because they are
innately ready for that part versus the
price Behavior which is what you said
it's not that but it's also the the
service element Etc so people so then
you are not addressing that part of the
customer shopping around from a price
perspective in some sense not
necessarily someone that's what I said
we track customer buying behaviors if
someone wants to come and buy from an
isoslombard they can come and buy from
myself.com right but they there is no
assurance that he or she will find the
cheapest from Isis Illinois okay let me
ask this question even more in another
fashion are you saying from the
behavioral tracking that people who buy
it on online portals essentially the
quality of the insurance underwritten
they are customer that could vary
between experienced experience that
could vary between experience to
experience because it also depends on
what model are you kind of getting your
policies bought for each model May
exhibit a loss experience which could be
very different okay so there are
multiple factors to the loss outcome so
the only point that I am trying to make
is we will never want to be compared
ourselves as even in some models we may
be by far the best in price but we never
want to lend a brand of Isis Lombard to
a platform which significantly sells on
price as a means to drive businesses
service is the element what will be
largely comfortable with which is the
point that I am making and second is we
do compare the relative cost of sourcing
which I would exhibit to a platform and
the same amount of money if I were to
spend in digital marketing between the
two Which is far more efficient so far
we have seen far more efficiency getting
created internally
in terms of value of business it's about
four percent of the total premium that
we write across business across
businesses in terms of large it is and
in terms of count of policies is about
nine to ten percent because it's a
relatively small ticket evidence you
look for for that transition one is use
hard marketing numbers digital internal
sourcing versus third party what the
platform demands yeah the cut or the
kickback tomorrow if any of this become
platform starts to become too bigger
platform where you cannot avoid kind of
working with those platforms at that
point of time we will think so that
that's so you're you're saying that
industry scale we don't think at this
point of time which is by the point that
I made one is they become too big a
platform for us to kind of ignore right
second
customers suddenly starting to move
everything to buy online we will kind of
track those buying Journeys
foreign
could we be closer to 65 there is also a
claim inflation as well right yeah so
there's also an element of claim
inflation so which is why we give that
range we are okay to kind of run the
retail Health portfolio at a loss ratio
range of 65 to 70. which kind of factors
in for whatever price increases that we
have to make plus the anticipated claim
inflation that one is
what is that operating level is coming
on like which expense
it could be multiple expenses you have
to look at it overall from the cost of
doing business which is why that
expensive management threshold
information
all that I'm saying is you should look
at the relative scale today when I'm
investing on employees who are joining
on the roles of Isis Lombard that's a
fixed cost to me I don't have a
denominator for it
those employees of mine have to kind of
get 15 to 20 000 agents on board first
right now we are at about 10 000 number
that's a number that we put out last
time so that's the number 20 000 agents
fifteen to twenty thousand agents at
least they should add a thousand
employees plus we're making investment
this year as well so they need to add 15
to 20. they need to start becoming
productive today none of them are then a
denominator so automatically my expense
issue will start to look better today my
expense ratios are adverse because my
denominator is lower
so there is operating average in which
of course of course there's an operating
leverage in this and then your
bargaining power with hospitals which is
a constant dialogue that we will do not
just in health but across lines of
business so two x three x are size of
right now retail so let me give a I can
only tell you over the years if you look
at my head count productivity number
again we don't want to look at one or
two years numbers if you look at again
2008 to 2022
my head count numbers would have dropped
by roughly 40 percent
from the peak in 2008 to where we are in
2022 my policy count would have
increased almost over eight X
and therefore consistently over a
14-year cycle my head contractivity is
roughly about 15 percent
15 annualized I have 15 cagr year on
Year annualized and that continues even
with these Investments this is about a
14-year cycle because each of these
Innovations will start to play out over
a point of time which is why if you look
at it over a two year cycle it will be a
very easier exactly you will show a very
low number but you have to look at it
over Cycles that's it either I gave it
to you later
period our objective will
you try and see if you can maintain
maintain the head contractor that's what
we would lastly
so with this motor uh you know the
sanctity in the pricing is